

07946 538 191 me@barryhalper.com www.barryhalper.com www.github.com/barryhalper ♀



PROFILE

I am a highly motivated full-stack web developer with over twenty years experience delivering market-leading business-to-business brands. I have extensive knowledge in web development, database architecture, web design, SEO, and server/domain management. As a technical lead, I have experience in team building, managing developers, determining project requirements, liaising with both internal and external clients to deliver projects that increase profits, and drive efficiency.



EXPERIENCE

Hemming Group Ltd 2000-2020 WEB DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Fulfilling the roles of application architect, technical lead and SQL DBA I was responsible for creating and managing a range of business applications, CRMs, CMS and REST APIs for the publishing and events business.

I implemented innovations in data storage, e-commerce, publishing and customer fulfilment. I upgraded the development platform (from CF to .NET) and helped steer the business towards iterative, agile development using the latest web technologies/frameworks, UX standards and SEO best practices. As a manager, I helped create the Hemming web team of developers, designers and a project manager. I worked with a multi-disiplinary team to help create business requirement documents and wrote application documentation and security guidlines.

SENIOR DEVELOPER 2005-2008

Responsible for hiring and managing a team of developers to deliver web solutions for the publishing business.e,g the development of a company CMS used to publish *localgov.*co.uk content (and its sister titles) on a single custom-



EDUCATION

M.A. - Literature Culture & Modernity University of London 1996-1998

B.A.(hons) - English Literature & History (2:1) Manchester University 1990 -1993

Greenhill College, Harrow

3 A Levels & 6 GCSE'S (including maths & english) 1987-1990



SKILLS

.NET Framework/Core, C#, MVC, Web Forms, REST API, Entity Framework, LinqToSQL, Coldfusion Enterprise Server, Verity, Fusebox, CFscript, Javascript ES5 & 6, JQuery, JSON, Babel, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, XML, XSD, MS IIS, MS Windows Server, DNS management, MS SQL Server, MS SQL Management Studio, T-SQL, MongoDB, Compass, MS Visual Studio, Dreamweaver, LinqPad, Eclipse, Subversion, Tortoise SVN, Git Hub, external Web services (REST, SOAP, Oauth) Postman, Photoshop, MS Access applications (VBscript), e-commerce, Stripe, Worldpay, SEO best practices, responsive design, agile, TTD

built platform. I successfully delivered directory and data sales web applications for the local government sector by generating significate revenues. I implemented code standards, naming conventions and frameworks (fusebox) for the team. I provisioned hosting services and set up web servers.

WEB DEVELOPER 2003-2005

I created the front and back end of websites for the publishing business using Coldfusion and MS SQL Server e.g. Lingerie Buyer, Company Clothing and Bridge Design & Engineering. I also created intranet applications for email marketing and subscription fulfilment. I introduced e-commerce to the business through Worldpay integration and implemented Google Analytics for all sites.

EDITOR 2002-2003

I produced a newsletter on local government tenders, wrote reviews and features in Company Clothing Magazine and was the editor for Municipal Yearbook Procurement Guide.

RESEARCH & DEVELOPMENT ASSITANT 2000-2001

I converted Filemaker databases into MS Access and created desktop applications for the data entry teams using SQL & VBsrcript. Latterly I upgraded those databases to MS SQL server for online use. I was reposnible for the applications that exported data out of SQL into QuarkXpress for print publishing. I aslo created online HTML forms.

Company Clothing 1998-2000 RESEARCH ASSISTANT

I was responsible for compiling the subscription data for the company's various magazines and trade shows. I also created and launched a successful fax /email tendering service for subscribers.

Hammicks Legal Bookshop 1994-1995 HEAD OF SUBSCRIPTIONS

I ran the subscriptions/mail order department responsible for postal orders to the Inns of Court and legal services in Central London.

Blackwells bookshop 1993-1994

BOOKSELLER

I ran the fiction and history sections.

Freelance Web Developer 1998-2004

While at the Hemming Group I also worked freelance, building websites for local businesses such an estate agent, two architectural firms as well as working with graphic designers from the Royal Academy on a project that received funding from the Arts Council.



TRAINING COURSES

MS Access and SQL 2001 Introduction to Coldfusion 2001 Dreamweaver Ultradev 2001 MS Project 2003 Advanced Coldfusion 2004 Search Engine Optimisation Best Pratice 2004 Time Management 2005 The Newly appointed manager 2006 ASP.NET Programming in C# 2009 Angular JS 2017



HOBBIES

I am an avid reader, film buff and member if the

I love all types of music, play rhythm guitar and attend gigs as often as possible

I am passionate about good food and regularly cook for friends and family

I keep fit by regular walking and swimming I am fascinated by history both modern and ancient

I like to discover new places and have travelled widely

I spent year learning Japanese

O

RECENT PROJECTS

Municipal Yearbook: Public Spend https://www.mybpublicspend.com

A B2B application that aggregates spending data published by UK Councils over the last 5 years, presenting it to subscribers in a suite of custom-built web reporting tools The project consists of a subscriber-only web application and a CMS/CRM that allows the data team to upload data from XML and CSV artefacts and manage user fulfilment. Built on the Microsoft stack of SQL Server 2016, ASP.NET framework, MVC and Entity Framework, and utilising test-driven development, the application includes various data warehousing, indexing and caching techniques as well as JQuery and a Rest API to optimise the performance of a data set of over 48,000,000 rows. This ensures the complex algorithms that aggregate data can render efficiently a range of customer-defined, reports, charts, and datasets. As well as building all the database architecture and applications I also created the UX using good practice web design based on industry standards of HTML5 and Twitter Bootstrap, Javascript and helped in the creation of the marketing site by the front end team.

Hemming Publishing CMS

This directory is a market leader in online repositories providing the most current information on all UK local government officers and elected officials. For this project, I created and managed a subscription-based web application, an editorial CRM and a client-facing RESTFUL API. The SQL database and .NET web application features payment based access and entitlement (using Stripe), order progression and subscription fulfilment as well as complex data analysis and reporting. The web application provides an intuitive user interface to help users access the information quickly and efficiently and has a customisable dashboard so subscribers can target key information to help make smart business decisions. To this end, I employed a team of designers and third party testers to deliver this project on time and on budget. I also worked closely with the editorial departments to create a CRM to manage the whole cycle of data collation and entry. I also created and ran the process that enabled editorial to export the data from SQL to Indesign for physical publication.

Localgov https://www.localgov.co.uk

The UK's largest dedicated local government news website. I led a team of contractors to deliver this project using Coldfusion, Javascript, Ajax and MS SQL server. The product was successfully launched in January 2006, winning in its first few months a special recommendation industry award. The project includes a custom-built CMS Full-Text searches, a REST API and integrations tools with third-party providers. A good example of iterative development across the full stack, I have redesigned and rebuilt this site using C# .Net web forms then NET.MVC and bootstrap 3 based on responsive design principles. The design template for the site has been reused for many other titles in the Hemming portfolio.

Municipal Yearbook https://www.municipalyearbook.co.uk

This directory is a market leader in online repositories providing the most current information on all UK local government officers and elected officials. For this project, I created and managed a subscription-based web application, an editorial CRM and a client-facing RESTFUL API. The SQL database and .NET web application features payment based access and entitlement (using Stripe), order progression and subscription fulfilment as well as complex data analysis and reporting. The web application provides an intuitive user interface to help users access the information quickly and efficiently and has a customisable dashboard so subscribers can target key information to help make smart business decisions. To this end, I employed a team of designers and third party testers to deliver this project on time and on budget. I also worked closely with the editorial departments to create a CRM to manage the whole cycle of data collation and entry. I also created and ran the process that enabled editorial to export the data from SQL to Indesign for physical publication.